A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office Files of Alison R. Bernstein FA573
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Office Files of Alison R. Bernstein
1974-2010
Rockefeller Archive Center
Bernstein, Alison R. (1947-2016)
Ford Foundation
FA573
31.69 Cubic Feet 79 letter document containers, 2 half letter document containers, 1 legal document container
Scope and Contents
The collection documents the various roles Alison Bernstein held at the Ford Foundation between 1983 and 2010, including program officer, director of the Education and Culture program, and Vice President of the Education, Creativity and Free Expression Program, later called Creativity and Free Expression.
The collection includes Education, Media, Arts and Culture grant documents, chronological correspondence files, materials related to the Ford Foundation's African Higher Education Initiative, women's programs, international fellowships program files, Difficult Dialogues program correspondence and papers, Ford Foundation publications and reports, Ford Foundation program leadership material, files related to Ford Foundation Education and Culture programs abroad, articles by and about Bernstein, keynote speeches, field office chronological files, Board of Trustees meeting materials, program officer memos, staff retreat documents, and meeting and trip files, including briefing books, correspondence, and agendas from Ford visits to China, Egypt, France, Ghana, Russia, South Africa, and Vietnam.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
Arranged in 4 series:
1: Program Officer Files, 1987-1990
2. Director Files, 1991-1993
3. Vice President Files, 1974-2007
4. Executive Officer Subject Files, 1975-2010
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Alison Bernstein worked at the Ford Foundation from 1983 until 2010, with a break in the early 1990s to assume the position of Associate Dean of the Faculty at Princeton University. Bernstein started as a program officer in 1983, and she was named director of Education and Culture at the Foundation in 1992. In 1996, Bernstein was later promoted to vice president of the Ford Foundation's Education, Creativity and Free Expression Program, later called called Creativity and Free Expression. In 2011, Bernstein left the Foundation to become the director of the Institute for Women's Leadership at Rutgers University.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The material in this collection was transferred from the Ford Foundation in 2012, 2017, 2018, and 2021 and ingested by RAC as Accessions 2012:034, 2017:077, 2017:090, 2018:037, and 2021:085.
- Program Officer Files, 1987-1990; 1; 2.47 Cubic Feet
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1987 July-1990 February (Box 1, Folder 1-6, Box 2, Folder 7-10)
    Arrangement
    Individual folders arranged in reverse chronological order
  - Alphabetical Correspondence Files A-Z, 1987 April-1990 February (Box 2, Folder 11, Box 3, Folder 12-16, Box 4, Folder 17-18)
  - Updated Women's Program Forum (WPF) List, 1989 October 13 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Women's Studies/Request for Proposal Letter - Southwest Institute for Research on Women (SIROW), University of Arizona, Tucson, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Questionnaire for Women's Policy Forum (WPF), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Domestic Consultant Forms for Helen Cunningham Newbold, S. Zwerling, Ed Hatton for Developing Grant Recommendations, 1990 February 26 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Domestic Consultant Forms - Education and Culture Program Latin American Studies Association Conference, NY, 1989 June 21-23 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Access to Higher Education Program - Mexican American Legal Defense and Educational Fund (MALDEF), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Hagopian, Harold - Armenian Music Letter, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - National Council for Research on Women - Address List for Women's Centers, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Request for Proposal - Consultants Letter - Panel, 1988 March-May (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Scope and Contents
    RFP sent March 29, 1988 - Review panel for competition to integrate research on minority women into undergraduate liberal arts curriculum
  - Proposal Review Session Letters to Panelists - Minority Women Program, 1988 October 26 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Letters asking Rutgers, Barnard, Columbia, Memphis State, and George Washington University to Resubmit, 1988 November 4 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Letters regarding the Foundation's Minority Women's Studies Program
  - Minority Women's Studies Competition Rejection Letters, Brown, Cincinnati, University of Texas, Smith, 1988 November 15 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Women's Studies/Request for Proposal Letter - Project on Women and Social Change - Smith College, 1988 February (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Women's Studies/ Request for Proposal Letter - Center for Women's Studies - University of Cincinnati, 1988 May 5 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - FY 1988-1989 Budget Projections (Box 5, Folder 33-34)
  - Task Force of Donors to African Education Report on Meeting, Vienna, Austria, 1990 July 23-25 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - A Proposal for the Development of the Association for Examinations and Educational Assessment in East and Southern Africa, Higher Education for Development Co-operation (HEDCO), 1990 March (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Rwanda - Report on School Examination and Educational System, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Using Examinations to Improve Education: A Study in Fourteen African Countries - Synthesis Report - Volume I: Findings and Recommendations (2 copies), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Using Examinations to Improve Education: A Study in Fourteen African Countries - Synthesis Report - Volume II: Costed Action Plans (2 copies), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - PWS Desk File - Special and Miscellaneous Reports (Black and Hispanic Museum/Green), 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 40-41)
  - PWS Desk File - Soviet Union Eastern Europe Study Group (Carmichael et al.), 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 42-43, Box 7, Folder 44-45)
- Director Files, 1991-1993; 2; 1.14 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes
  - Education and Culture Correspondence - Berresford/Gaberman/Jaffe, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Education and Culture Docket Text, 1993 March (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Important Staff Memos for Action (From Susan V. Berresford, Barry D. Gaberman, et al.), 1992 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Trustees Correspondence/Information, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence To/From Director (4 folders), 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 50-53)
  - General Information (Budget/Education and Culture Codes/Staff Assignments), 1992 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - To/From President/Chairman (Franklin Thomas and Edson Spencer), 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence - Interoffice (Other Programs) (2 folders), 1992 (Box 9, Folder 56)
    Governance and Public Policy, Program Related Investments - Miller, Rural Poverty - E. Walter Coward, Urban Poverty R. Curvin
  - 1992 Annual Report - Drafts, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence - Office of Communications, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence - Interoffice, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - US International Affairs Program (USIAP) Administration Grant Correspondence (Maxine Gaddis/Roberta Lynch/Susan Shea/Michele Cole), 1992 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Developing Country Program, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Travel Records, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Barry Gaberman Chronological Files (4 folders), 1992 (Box 10, Folder 63-66)
    Folder 62: A-D Folder 63 E-Q Folder 64: R-Z
- Vice President Files, 1974-2007; 6.08 Cubic Feet 16 letter document boxes
  - Aguerrebere, Joseph - Program Division Leadership Meeting, 1999 December (Box 11, Folder 67)
  - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC) Delegated Authority Grants (DAGs) - US and Overseas by Field Office, 2000-2002 (Box 11, Folder 68-69)
  - Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC)/Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR) - FY 2002 Delegated Authority Grants (DAGs) (Box 11, Folder 70, Box 12, Folder 71)
  - Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC)/Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR) - FY 2002 Recommended Grant Action (RGAs) (Box 12, Folder 72-73)
  - Agendas/Office of Vice President (OVP) - FY 2002 Recommended Grant Actions (RGAs), 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 74)
  - FY 2002 Recommended Grant Actions (RGAs) - Overseas (by Office) (Box 12, Folder 75, Box 13, Folder 76-78)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - Briefing Book, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 79)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - Meeting of the Presidents, 2005 February 23 (Box 14, Folder 80)
    Meeting of the Presidents of Carnegie Corporation, The Ford Foundation, William and Flora Hewlett Foundation, John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, and The Rockefeller Foundation
  - African Higher Education Success Stories, 2005 July 1 (Box 14, Folder 81)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - Partnership Event - Trustee and VIP Invites, 2005 September 16 (Box 14, Folder 82)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - Partnership Event, 2005 September 16 (Box 14, Folder 83)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - Meeting of the Presidents, 2005 November 17 (Box 14, Folder 84)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - Meeting of the Presidents, 2006 February 23 (Box 14, Folder 85)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - Collaboration between Rockefeller Foundation/Carnegie Foundation/MacArthur Foundation/Ford Foundation, 1999-2005 (Box 14, Folder 86-87)
  - African Higher Education Initiative Partnerships - Contracts, 2006 (Box 15, Folder 88-90)
  - The Partnership for African Higher Education, Narciso Matos, International Higher Education, Number 44, 2006 (Box 15, Folder 91)
  - African Higher Education Meeting Materials, 2005-2006 (Box 15, Folder 92)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - Introduction to Ford Foundation Reports on African American Studies, Farah J. Griffin, 2005 July (Box 15, Folder 93)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - Meeting with Leaders of African Higher Education, 2005 September (Box 15, Folder 94)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - Overview and Meeting Information, 2005 September 16 (Box 15, Folder 95)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - Nairobi Documents - Memorandum of Understanding, Ford Foundation Staff Roles and Responsibilities, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 96)
  - Partnerships for Higher Education in Africa Presidents Meeting, 2003 November 17 (Box 15, Folder 97)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - Meeting of the Presidents, 2004 November 29 (Box 15, Folder 98)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - Partnership for Higher Education: Lunch, 2005 September 16 (Box 15, Folder 99)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - General, 2004-2007 (Box 15, Folder 100)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - Alison Bernstein Information Packet, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 101)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - Information Pack, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 102)
  - African Higher Education Initiative - Meeting of the Presidents, 2007 April 27 (Box 16, Folder 103-106)
  - Frontiers of Knowledge: In Science and Technology for Africa, University Leaders' Forum, University of Cape Town, undated; CD-R (Box 16)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Open for research. Digital access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - Ford Foundation International Fellowships Program - Discussion, 2001 April 16 (Box 16, Folder 107)
  - Ford Foundation International Fellowships Program - Board of Directors Meeting, 2003 January 13 (Box 16, Folder 108)
  - Ford Foundation International Fellowships Program - Board of Directors Meeting, 2003 January 13 (Box 17, Folder 109)
  - Ford Foundation International Fellowships Program, Leadership for Social Justice, Inaugural Leadership Institute, 2002 July (Box 17, Folder 109)
  - Appalshop - NYC, China - Appalachian Presentation Outline, 2003 November 10 (Box 17, Folder 110)
  - ITVS (Independent Television Service) - Sally Jo Fifer, 2003 December 8 (Box 17, Folder 111)
  - International Fellowships Program, 2003-2004 (Box 17, Folder 112)
  - Leadership for a Changing World - General, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 113)
  - Leadership for a Changing World - Final Evaluation Report, 2006 February (Box 17, Folder 114)
  - International Fellowships Fund - General, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 115)
  - Joint Meeting of the Program Advisory Committee and Board of Directors, International Fellowships Fund - Oaxaca, Mexico, 2004 January 15 (Box 17, Folder 116)
  - International Fellowships Fund - Board of Directors Meeting, 2004 September 13 (Box 18, Folder 117)
  - International Fellowships Program - Finance and Investment Advisory Committee, 2004 (Box 18, Folder 118)
  - International Fellowships Fund - Board of Directors Meeting, 2005 January 10 (Box 18, Folder 119)
  - International Fellowships Fund - Update Meeting, 2005 January (Box 18, Folder 120)
  - International Fellowships Program - Program Advisory Committee Meeting, 2005 March 14-15 (Box 18, Folder 121-122)
  - International Fellowships Program - Reception, 2005 March 15 (Box 18, Folder 123)
  - International Fellowships Fund - Board of Directors Meeting, 2005 May 9 (Box 18, Folder 124)
  - International Fellowships Program - Leadership for Social Justice Institute 8, Catholic University of America, 2005 June 12-17 (Box 18, Folder 125)
  - International Fellowships Program - Washington, D.C. Visit, 2005 June 15 (Box 18, Folder 126)
  - International Fellowships Fund - Board of Directors Meeting, 2006 January 30 (Box 18, Folder 127)
  - International Fellowships Fund - Board of Directors Meeting, 2006 May 8 (Box 18, Folder 128)
  - Ad Hoc Consultations on a Track II Process - Briefing Book and Schedule - Reduce and Remove the Impact of Agent Orange/Dioxin in Vietnam, 2007 February 10-16 (Box 19, Folder 129)
  - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC) Worldwide Meeting, Brazil, 2001-2006 (Box 19, Folder 130)
  - Centro Latino-Americano em Sexualidade e Direitos Humanos, 2004 December; CD (Box 19)
  - Committee on Indigenous Peoples - Learning Forum: Making Local, National, and International Partnerships Work, 2005 May 20 (Box 19, Folder 131)
  - Difficult Dialogues - Reports, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 132)
    Bridging Middle East Tensions on U.S. Campuses: What Can Be Done?, Myra Dinnerstein
    Summary Report of the Conference, "Maintaining a Free and Open Campus Environment," Hosted by the Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Program of the Ford Foundation, Karen Kennerly
  - Difficult Dialogues - Leonard Dinnerstein - Correspondence on Programmatic Suggestions, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 133)
  - Difficult Dialogues - Promoting Religious Pluralism and Academic Freedom on Campus, Miami, 2004-2005 (Box 19, Folder 134)
  - Difficult Dialogues - Antisemitism Task Force, 2004-2005 (Box 19, Folder 135)
  - Difficult Dialogues - Request for Proposal - Promoting Religious Pluralism and Academic Freedom on Campus, Miami, 2004-2005 (Box 19, Folder 136)
  - Difficult Dialogues - Thank Yous, 2005 April (Box 19, Folder 137)
  - Difficult Dialogues - Grantees List, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 138)
  - Difficult Dialogues - Final List, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 139)
  - Difficult Dialogues - American Association of University Professors (AAUP) Correspondence, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 140)
  - Difficult Dialogues - Request for Proposals, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 141)
  - Difficult Dialogues - Recommendation for Grant Actions (RGAs), 2006 (Box 19, Folder 142)
  - Difficult Dialogues - News Articles, 2005 April (Box 19, Folder 143)
  - Difficult Dialogues - Recommendation for Grant Actions (RGAs), 2006 (Box 19, Folder 144)
  - Difficult Dialogues - Readers Correspondence, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 145)
  - Difficult Dialogues - Northeastern Regional Conference, New Haven, 2007 January 11 (Box 20, Folder 146)
  - Difficult Dialogues - Religious Grantees, 2006 September-October (Box 20, Folder 147)
  - Difficult Dialogues - Ford Foundation Workshop - Exploring Aspects of Grantmaking in Europe, Stephan Batory Foundation, Poland, 2006 June 14-15 (Box 20, Folder 148)
  - Diversity Fellows - Edgar Beckham - Diversity Luncheon at the Ford Foundation, 2004 June 10 (Box 20, Folder 149)
  - Diversity Fellows - Edgar Beckham - Tri-National Seminar on Diversity Issues in Higher Education - Materials, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 150)
  - Diversity Fellows - Edgar Beckham - Diversity Letter to University Presidents, 2004 July (Box 20, Folder 151)
  - Diversity Fellows - Edgar Beckham - Diversity Fellows Trustee Conference Invitation, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 152)
  - Fulfilling the Dream Fund Donor Meeting, 2004 October 19-20 (Box 20, Folder 153)
  - Education and Culture Teamwork Project, 1996 January-June (Box 20, Folder 154)
  - Exploring Europe Grantmaking Group (EEGG), 2006 (Box 20, Folder 155-156)
  - Piper Fogg Interview - Chronicle of Higher Education, 2005 March 30 (Box 21, Folder 157)
  - Ford Foundation Media and Arts and Culture (MAC) Grantmaking: Historical Profile, 1951-2001 (Lynn E. Stern), 2003 (Box 21, Folder 158)
  - The Ford Foundation, Media Program Portfolio Review 1988-1998, Prepared by Angel Zapata, BrightLight Communications, 1999 April (Box 21, Folder 159)
  - The Ford Foundation - 10 Years in Russia, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 160)
  - Fund for Community Organizing - Assessing Community Change: An Evaluation of the Community Organizing Initiative, 2006 April (Box 21, Folder 161)
  - Hip Hop Convening, 2003 November 5 (Box 21, Folder 162)
  - ICPD (International Conference on Population and Development) + 10 World Leader Statements (Susan Berresford), 2004 (Box 21, Folder 163)
  - Institute of International Education - Scholar Rescue Fund Case Report, 2007 May (Box 21, Folder 164)
  - International Fellowships Program Advisory Committee, 2000-2004 (Box 22, Folder 165)
  - International Fellowships Fund - Board of Directors Meeting, 2002 June 24 (Box 22, Folder 166)
  - International Fellowships Fund - Board of Directors Meeting, 2003 May 12 (Box 22, Folder 167)
  - International Fellowships Fund - Board of Directors Meeting, 2003 September 8 (Box 22, Folder 168)
  - International Fellowships Program - Updates and Grants, 2001 (Box 22, Folder 169)
  - International Fellowships Program Report, 2003-2004 (Box 22, Folder 170)
  - International Fellowships Fund - Board of Directors Meeting, 2004 May 10 (Box 22, Folder 171)
  - Steve Lawry Luncheon on Liberal Education and Civic Engagement, 2006 June 21 (Box 22, Folder 172)
  - MLK Library - Mayor Shirley Franklin, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 173)
  - Rutgers Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom (KCF) Retreat, 2005 (Box 22, Folder 174)
  - Stone Soup Seminar, 2004 March 5 (Box 23, Folder 175)
  - Trip File - Paris, France (French-American Foundation Conference), 2003 March 6-7 (Box 23, Folder 176)
  - Vietnam Ministry of Health Meeting, 2006 (Box 23, Folder 177)
  - Susan V. Berresford Correspondence, 2003-2005 (Box 23, Folder 178)
  - The First Emperor Piano Workshop, Metropolitan Opera, 2006 (Box 23, Folder 179)
  - The International Freedom Center Draft Content Concept Papers (and Supporting Documentation), 2005 February 15 (Box 23, Folder 180)
  - World Trade Center Memorial Foundation, Update to the Ford Foundation, 2005 March 2 (Box 23, Folder 181)
  - That 51 Per Cent: Ford Foundation Activities Related to Opportunities for Women (Report 019836), 1974 (Box 23, Folder 182)
  - That 51%... Plus (Report 019837), 1979 (Box 23, Folder 183)
  - Looking Back, Moving Ahead: A Decade of School Finance Reform, A Ford Foundation Reprint, James A. Kelly (01736), 1980 (Box 23, Folder 184)
  - The Political Economy of Education: A Bibliography of Ford Foundation Supported Publications (Reports 019839), 1980 (Box 23, Folder 185)
  - Status Report on the Education and Culture Program (Report 019840), 1983 (Box 23, Folder 186)
  - Created Equal: A Report on the Ford Foundation's Women's Programs (Reports 019841), 1986 (Box 23, Folder 187)
  - ...And Gladly Teach: A Ford Foundation Report on the Urban Mathematics Collaboratives (Report 019842), 1987 (Box 23, Folder 188)
  - The Education and Culture Program's Math and Science Program (Report 019843), 1988 December (Box 23, Folder 189)
  - Feminist Pluralism, Ford Foundation Women's Program Forum, Eleanor Holmes Norton (07281), 1987 (Box 23, Folder 190)
  - Ford Foundation Annual Reports - Education and Culture, 1988; 1991-1992 (Box 23, Folder 191)
  - Task Force 2000: Creating 21st Century Schools - Draft (Reports 019844), 1989 October 25 (Box 23, Folder 192)
  - Toward a New Professorate: A Review of the Ford Foundation Initiative in Undergraduate Education, Dr. Frederick L. Campbell (Report 012312), 1990 February 28 (Box 24, Folder 193)
  - Foundation-Supported Commissions: Lessons for their Creation and Management, Joan R. Wynn (Report 012789), 1991 July (Box 24, Folder 194)
  - Diversity in American Higher Education, Education and Culture Committee Discussion Paper (Report 012247), 1992 June (Box 24, Folder 195)
  - The Ford Foundation and the Urban Poor in the 1950s, Alice O'Connor (Reports 019845), 1993 October 21 (Box 24, Folder 196)
  - Education and Culture 1994-1995 Biennium Budget and Program Paper (Reports 019846), 1993 (Box 24, Folder 197)
  - Draft - History of the Ford Foundation's Programmatic Philosophies 1950-1994: K-12 School Reform, Charles Wright, Jr. (Report 019847) (Box 24, Folder 198)
  - Anti-Delinquency, Great Cities, Gray Areas, Kathleen D. McCarthy (Reports 019848), 1987-1994 (Box 24, Folder 199)
  - Reflections on the Ford Foundation's Worldwide Workshop on Culture, Toby Alice Volkman (Report 012650), 1995 (Box 24, Folder 200)
  - Achieving Diversity in the Professoriate: Challenges and Opportunities (Report 012955), 1996 (Box 24, Folder 201)
  - The Role of the Ford Foundation Fellowship Program for Minorities in the Production of PhDs (Report 019849), 1997 October (Box 24, Folder 202)
  - Report on Women's Studies Consultancy (Report 012847), 1998 February 26 (Box 24, Folder 203)
  - Review of Ford Foundation Grants on Language (Report 016288), 1999 (Box 24, Folder 204)
  - School Accountability - Memos and Articles, 2000 June 30 (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Using a Theory of Change Approach to Articulate and Evaluate Three Constituency Building Organizations Activities and Outcomes: Update and Reflections (Report 015435), 2000 November (Box 24, Folder 206)
  - Evaluation of 21st Century School Fund "Theory of Change" (Report 015436), 2000 (Box 25, Folder 207)
  - The Impact of Challenges to Race-Based Admissions and Financial Aid on Minority Fellowships (Report 011305), 2000 January 10 (Box 25, Folder 208)
  - A Review of Afro-American Studies Programs for the Ford Foundation, Dianne M. Pinderhughes and Richard Yarborough (Report 015432), 2000 (Box 25, Folder 209)
  - Ford Foundation Report Magazine, 1995-2003 (Box 25, Folder 210)
  - 40 Years: A Learning Curve: The Ford Foundation in India, 1952-1992, Eugene S. Staples (Report 017460) (Box 25, Folder 211)
  - Forestry for Sustainable Rural Development: A Review of Ford Foundation-Supported Community Forestry Programs in Asia, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 212)
  - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC) Annual Retreat, Tarrytown Conference Center (Report 013646), 1999 September 21-22 (Box 25, Folder 213)
  - Ford Foundation President's Message, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 214)
  - Solving the Math Problem: Ford Foundation's Work on Reforming Middle and Secondary School Mathematics, 1980-1988, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 215)